TOBIAS CANAVESI

Data Scientist, PhD

♠ tobiascanavesi



PERSONAL PROFILE

I consider myself in love with mathematics and the Universe. I have a bachelor degree in Astronomy and a PhD in theoretical physics. I also like technology (particularly Artificial Intelligence). I did Data Science courses and i have experience working in important projects across various industries. I'm a versatile person, capable of adapting to any task or problem to solve. I enjoy working with people from different areas because i think that multidisciplinary collaboration is key to the advancement of society.

ACTUAL POSITION

Senior Data Scientist Heyday

December 2022 - Ongoing

- **Q** United States, Remotely
- Create analytical solutions in SQL and Python to address various needs.
- Improve forecasting capabilities and accuracy for over 7000 products by utilizing AI techniques, including automating the entire workflow in Airflow. (AWS)
- Work on NLP-related projects.
- Develop various projects from scratch to automation.
- Agent creation using LangChain and LLM models to obtain sales insights. (Streamlit+Python)

PREVIOUS POSITION

Specialist Data Scientist

Accenture

Mov 2021 - Dec 2022

P Buenos Aires, Argentina

 Manage, architect and analyze big data in order to build data driven business insights and high impact data models to generate significant business value. Create models and processes to collect, distill and interpret data with a view to aid better, more informed decision making.

Postgraduate professor University of Buenos Aires

May 2022 - Jun 2023

Q Buenos Aires, Argentina

 Postgraduate professor at the School of Engineering of the University of Buenos Aires, teaching the course Machine Learning I for the Artificial Intelligence Specialization Course (CEIA).

LANGUAGES

MY LIFE PHILOSOPHY

"Every problem has a solution, even if the solution is in another problem."

SKILLS



Work in group

Ability to work in a group, either leading or being part of it



Programming

Programming in different languages mainly in Python and Mathematica.



Data Science Skills

Data wrangling, Data Visualization, ability to understand a problem in depth in order to be able to use the appropriate machine learning and deep learning tools. Segmentation, forecasting, regression and classification. Automation.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python
- Wolfram
- SQL
- Problem solving skills
- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Cloud

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Theoretical Physics National University of La Plata

BSc. in Astronomy National University of La Plata

2019 - 2017

Data Science Specialization Digital House

mar 2021 - Sep 2021

Deep Learning Specialization

Deep Learning AI

🛗 Jan 2022 - No expiration date





SELECT EXPERIENCE

Demand Forecasting

Airline Company (Chile)

2022 - Ongoing

- Design, implementation and evaluation of machine learning models for time series forecasting.
- Forecast performance analysis comparing ML and time series models.
- Study on price elasticity of demand.

Simulation - Optimization

Mining Industry (Canada)

2022

- Part of the team in charge of creating a simulation and optimization model for water treatment. (Databricks + Azure)
- Agile project management (Azure DevOps).

Optimization

Mining Industry (Chile)

2022

• Creation of a water use optimization model. (Databricks + Azure)

Segmentation - Clustering

E-Commerce (LATAM)

2022

- Definition of metrics and algorithms for retraining clustering models.
- Application of statistics to understand a better application of promotions.

Demand Forecasting

Drinks company (Chile)

₩ 2021

- Design, implementation and evaluation of machine learning models for time series forecasting. (AWS - Sagemaker)
- Forecast performance analysis comparing ML and time series models. (AWS Sagemaker)

Instructor of the Wolfram Summer School 2021 Wolfram Research (United States)

2021

 Working as a mentor at the Wolfram 2021 summer school. https://education.wolfram.com/summer-school

CERTIFICATIONS

Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter Tuning, Regularization and Optimization Deep Learning AI

Apr 2022 - No expiration date

Structuring Machine Learning Projects

Deep Learning AI

Apr 2022 - No expiration date

Neural Networks and Deep Learning Deep Learning AI

Apr 2022 - No expiration date

Convolutional Neural Networks Deep Learning AI

Apr 2022 - No expiration date

Sequence Models

Deep Learning AI

iii Jun 2022 − No expiration date

Databases and SQL for Data Science with Python

Deep Learning AI

🛗 Jul 2022 - No expiration date

Introduction to Machine Learning in Production

Deep Learning AI

AWARDS

Thank you for being an Al Hero - Client Value Creation

Accenture

PUBLISHED RESEARCH

Visit my google scholar page Tobias Canavesi